Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852., 10 envelopes (Box 5, Item 46)
    - No, Not More Welcome. "No, not more welcome the fairy numbers" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - Oft, in the stilly night. "Oft, in the stilly night" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - Oh! Blame Not the Bard. "Oh! blame not the bard, if he fly to the bowers" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - Oh, Call It by Some Better Name. "Oh, call it by some better name" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - "Oh! ever thus, from childhood's hour" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - "Oh! ever thus, from childhood's hour," (Cont.) (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Oh the Shamrock. "Through Erin's Isle" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - One Bumper at Parting. "One bumper at parting! though many" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Paradise and the Peri. "One morn a Peri at the gate" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - The Prince's Day. "Tho' dark are our sorrows, to-day we'll forget them" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Rich and Rare Were the Gems She Wore. "Rich and rare were the gems she wore" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Rondeau. "'Good night! good night!' -And be it so?" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Sail on, Sail on. "Sail on, sail on, thou fearless bark -" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - She is Far From the Land. "She is far from the land where her young hero sleeps" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Susan. "Young Love lived once in an humble shed" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 6)
    - Susan. "Young Love lived once in an humble shed," (Cont.) (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - A Temple to Friendship. "'A Temple to Friendship,' said Laura, enchanted" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - Thee, Thee, Only Tee. "The dawning of morn, the daylight's sinking" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - There's a bower of roses. "There's a bower of roses by Bendemeer's stream" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - This Life Is All Chequer'd with Pleasures and Woes. "This life is all chequer'd with pleasures and woes" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - Tho' the Last Glimpse of Erin with Sorrow I See. "Tho' the last glimpse of Erin with sorrow I see" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - Those Evening Bells. "Those evening bells! those evening bells!" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 7)
    - Those Evening Bells. "Those evening bells! those evening bells!" (Cont.) (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 8)
    - The Time I've Lost in Wooing. "The time I've lost in wooing" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 8)
    - 'Tis the Last Rose of Summer. "'Tis the last rose of summer" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 8)
    - To Ladies' Eyes. "To Ladies' eyes around, boy" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - The Sigh, Yet Feel No Pain. "To sigh, yet feel no pain" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - When He Who Adores Thee. "When he who adores thee, has left but the name" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - While History's Muse the Memorial Was Keeping" "While History's Muses the memorial was keeping" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - Who'll Buy My Love-Knots?" "While Hyman, late, his love-knots selling" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - The Woodpecker. "I knew by the smoke, that so gracefully curl'd" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - Wreaths for the Ministers. "Hither, Flora, Queen of Flowers!" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - You Remember Ellen. "You remember Ellen, our hamlet's pride" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - The Young May Moon. "The young May moon is beaming, love" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 9)
    - General (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 10)
  - Morris, George Pope, 1802-1864., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 47)
    - Woodman, Spare That Tree! "Woodman, spare that tree!" (Box 5, Item 47)
  - Morris, Lewis., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 48)
    - Ode Sung at the First Cooperative Festival. August 17, 1888. "Come let us sing together a new song" (Box 5, Item 48)
    - Ode to the Imperial Institute. "With soaring voice and solemn music sing" (Box 5, Item 48)
  - Morris, William, 1834-1896., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 49)
    - Earthly Paradise. "In the white-flowered hawthorn brake" (Box 5, Item 49)
    - The Gilliflower of Gold. "A golden gilliflower to-day" (Box 5, Item 49)
    - Parodies in the style of Morris, original poem unidentified. (Box 5, Item 49)
  - Moss, Thomas., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 50)
    - The Beggar's Petition. "Pity the sorrows of a poor old man" (Box 5, Item 50)
  - Moxon, Edward., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 51)
    - "Hence, Care, and let me steep my drooping spirit" (Box 5, Item 51)
  - The Mule. "The mule-he has his faults, 'tis true,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 52)
  - My Nellie's Blue Eyes. "My Nellie's eyes are blue,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 53)
  - My Queen. "Where and how shall I earliest meet her,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 54)
  - Myers, Frederic William Henry, 1843-1901., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 55)
    - "Lo! when a man magnanimous and tender" (Box 5, Item 55)
  - Nairne, Lady Carolina., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 56)
    - The Hundred Pipers. "Wi' a hundred pipers an' a', an' a'" (Box 5, Item 56)
    - The Laird o' Cockpen. "The laird o' Cockpen he's proud and he's great" (Box 5, Item 56)
    - The Land of the Leal. "I'm wearin' awa', Jean" (Box 5, Item 56)
  - Neale, John Mason., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 57)
    - "Good King Wenceslas looked out" (Box 5, Item 57)
  - Newbolt, Sir Henry John, 1862-1938., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 58)
    - Admiral Death. "Boys, are ye calling a toast tonight?" (Box 5, Item 58)
    - Drake's Drum. "Drake he's in his hammock an' a thousand mile away" (Box 5, Item 58)
    - The Fighting Téméraire. "It was eight bells ringing" (Box 5, Item 58)
    - The Sailing of the Long-Ships. "They saw the cables loosened, they saw the gangways cleared" (Box 5, Item 58)
  - Noel, Thomas., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 59)
    - The Pauper's Drive. "There's a grim one-horse hearse in a jolly round trot:" (Box 5, Item 59)
  - Norton, Caroline (Sheridan), 1808-1877., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 60)
    - The Arab's Farewell to his Horse. "My beautiful! My beautiful! that standest meekly by" (Box 5, Item 60)
    - Bingen on the Rhine. "A Soldier of the Legion lay dying in Algiers--" (Box 5, Item 60)
    - Love Not. "Love not, love not! ye hapless sons of clay!" (Box 5, Item 60)
  - Noyes, Alfred, 1880-1958., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 61)
    - Drake. (Box 5, Item 61)
    - Sherwood. "Sherwood in the twilight, is Robin Hood awake?" (Box 5, Item 61)
  - "O, let me like a soldier fall", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 62)
  - O, that will be Joyful. "Here we suffer grief and pain,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 63)
  - O! 'Tis Love! 'Tis Love! "O! 'Tis love! 'Tis love! 'Tis love!", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 64)
  - Oh! Give Me But My Arab Steed. "Oh! give me but my Arab steed,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 65)
  - "Oh! the snow! the beautiful snow!", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 66)
  - O'Keeffe, John, 1747-1833., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 67)
    - I Am a Friar of Orders Grey. "I am a Friar of orders grey" (Box 5, Item 67)
    - A Master I Have, And I Am His Man. "A Master I Have, and I am his man" (Box 5, Item 67)
    - Old Towler. "Bright Chanticleer proclaims the dawn" (Box 5, Item 67)
    - The Wolf. "At the peaceful midnight hour" (Box 5, Item 67)
  - Only. "Only a face at the window,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 68)
  - Only a Lock of Her Hair., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 69)
  - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur W. E., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 70)
    - Song. "Has summer come without the rose" (Box 5, Item 70)
    - We are the music-makers" (Box 5, Item 70)
  - Over and Over Again. "Over and over again,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 71)
  - Over the Garden Wall. "Oh, my love stood under the walnut tree,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 72)
  - Patmore, Coventry Kersey Dighton, 1823-1896., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 73)
    - The Angel in the House. (Box 5, Item 73)
  - Payne, John Howard, 1791-1852., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 74)
    - Home, Sweet Home. "'Mid pleasures and palace though we may roam" (Box 5, Item 74)
  - Peacock, Thomas Love, 1785-1866., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 75)
    - Oh! Say Not Woman's Heart Is Bought. "Oh! say not woman's heart is bought" (Box 5, Item 75)
  - Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 76)
    - The Friar of Orders Gray. "It was a friar of orders gray" (Box 5, Item 76)
    - O Nancy! Wilt Thou Go With Me. "O Nancy, wilt, thou go with me" (Box 5, Item 76)
  - Philips, Ambrose, 1674-1749., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 77)
    - A Fragment of Sappho. "Bless'd as the immortal gods is he" (Box 5, Item 77)
  - Phillips, Stephen, 1868-1915., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 78)
    - Parodies in the style of Phillips, original poem unidentified. (Box 5, Item 78)
  - The Pilgrim of Love. "Orynthia, my beloved, I call in vain!", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 79)
  - Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849., 6 envelopes (Box 6, Item 1)
    - Annabel Lee. "It was many and many a year ago" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - The Bells. "Hear, the sledges with the bells-" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 1)
    - The Bells. "Hear, the sledges with the bells," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - The Coliseum. "Type of the antique Rome! Rich reliquary" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - The Conqueror Worm. "Lo! 'tis a gala night" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - Dreamland. "By a route obscure and lonely" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 2)
    - Eldorado. "Gaily bedight" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - For Annie. "Thank Heaven! The crisis,--" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - The Haunted Palace. "In the greenest of our valleys" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - Israfel. "In Heaven a spirit doth dwell" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - Lenore. "Ah, broken is the golden bowl! The spirit flown forever!" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - "Ligeia! Ligeia!" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - The Raven. "Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 3)
    - The Raven. "Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 4)
    - The Raven. "Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 5)
    - Silence. "There are some qualities-some incorporate things" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - To Helen. "Helen, thy beauty is to me" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - To Isadore. "Beneath the vine-clad eaves" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - To Zante. "Fair isle, that from the fairest of all flowers" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Ulalume. "The skies they were ashen and sober;" (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
    - Parodies in the style of Poe, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 1, Envelope 6)
  - Pollock, Walter Herries, 1850-1926., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 2)
    - The Devout Lover. "It is not mine to sing the stately grace" (Box 6, Item 2)
  - Pollok, Robert, 1798-1827., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 3)
    - The Course of Time. (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Polly. "Brown eyes,", 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 4)
  - Pop Goes the Weasel., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 5)
  - Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Achille's Speech. Now by this sacred scepter hear me swear" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - "As when the moon, refulgent lamp of night" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - The Dunciad. "The mighty mather, and her son, who brings" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - The Dying Christian to his Soul. "Vital spark of heavenly flame" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Essay on Man. "Lo, the poor Indian! whose untutored mind" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - "Here shall the spring her earliest sweets bestow" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Messiah. "Ye nymphs of Solyma! begin the song:" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Ode on St. Cecilia's Day. "Descend, ye Nine! descend and sing:" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Ode on Solitude. "Happy the man whose wish and care" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Pastoral. (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Rape of the Lock. (Box 6, Item 6)
    - To Mr. Addison's Tragedy of Cato. "to wake the soul by tender strokes of art" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - "Where Bentley late tempestuous wont to sport" (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Parodies in the style of Pope, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 6)
  - Pound, Ezra Loomis, 1885-1972., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 7)
    - Further Instructions. "Come, my songs, let us express our baser passions" (Box 6, Item 7)
    - Ortus. "How have I labored!" (Box 6, Item 7)
  - Praed, Winthrop Mackworth, 1802-183-, 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 8)
    - The Chant of the Brazen Head. "I think, whatever mortals crave" (Box 6, Item 8)
    - Good-Night to the Season. "Good-night to the Season! 'tis over!" (Box 6, Item 8)
    - I Remember, I Remember. "I remember-I remember" (Box 6, Item 8)
    - A Letter of Advice. "You tell me you're promised a lover" (Box 6, Item 8)
    - "No politics!-I cannot bear" (Box 6, Item 8)
    - Parody in the style of Praed, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 8)
  - Prentiss, Elizabeth (Payson), 1818-1878., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 9)
    - Cradle Song. "Sleep, baby, sleep!" (Box 6, Item 9)
  - Procter, Adelaide Anne, 1825-1864., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 10)
    - The Lost Chord. "Seated one day at the organ" (Box 6, Item 10)
    - Sent to Heaven. "I had a message to send her" (Box 6, Item 10)
    - A Woman's Question. "Before I trust my fate to thee" (Box 6, Item 10)
  - Procter, Bryan Waller, 1787-1874., 2 envelopes (Box 6, Item 11)
    - The Best of All Good Company. "Sing!-Who sings" (Box 6, Item 11, Envelope 1)
    - King Death. "King Death was a rare old fellow" (Box 6, Item 11, Envelope 1)
    - The Return of the Admiral. "How gallantly, how merrily, we ride along the sea!" (Box 6, Item 11, Envelope 1)
    - The Sea. "The sea! the sea! the open sea!" (Box 6, Item 11, Envelope 2)
  - Prowse, William Jeffrey, 1836-1870., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 12)
    - The City of Prague. "I dwelt in a city enchanted" (Box 6, Item 12)
  - Quiller-Couch, Sir Arthur Thomas, 1863-1944., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 13)
    - Sign hey! for the dead man's eyes, my lads;" (Box 6, Item 13)
    - The White Moth. "If a leaf rustled, she would start:" (Box 6, Item 13)
    - Parody in the style of Quiller-Couch, source poem unknown. (Box 6, Item 13)
  - Raleigh, Sir Walter, 1552?-1618., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 14)
    - His Love Admits No Rival. "Shall I, like a hermit, dwell" (Box 6, Item 14)
    - The Pilgrimage. "Give me my scallop-shell of quiet" (Box 6, Item 14)
    - The Soul's Errand. "Go, Soul, the body's guest" (Box 6, Item 14)
    - Parody in the style of Raleigh, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 14)
  - Randall, James Ryder, 1839-1908., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 15)
    - My Maryland. "The despot'd heel is on they shore" (Box 6, Item 15)
  - Rawnsley, Hardwicke Drummond, 1851-1920., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 16)
    - Parody in the style of Rawnsley, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 16)
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan, 1822-1872., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 17)
    - Sheridan's Ride. "Up from the south, at break of day" (Box 6, Item 17)
  - The Red Cross Knight. "Blow, warder, blow thy sounding horn,", 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 18)
  - Red, White and Blue., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 19)
  - Reynold, John Hamilton, 1794-1852., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 20)
  - Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916. (Box 6, Item 21)
    - A Life-Lesson- "there! Little girl, don't cry!" (Box 6, Item 21)
    - Little Orphant Annie. "Little Orphant Annie's come to our house to stay" (Box 6, Item 21)
    - Nothin' to Say. "Nothin' to say, my daughter! Nothin' at all to say!" (Box 6, Item 21)
    - When the Frost Is On the Punkin. "When the frost is on the punkin and the fodder's in the shock" (Box 6, Item 21)
    - Parodies in the style of Riley, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 21)
  - Robin Adair. "What's this dull town to me?", 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 22)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 23)
    - Parody in the style of Robinson, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 23)
  - Robinson, Edwin Meade., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 24)
    - Parody in the style Robinson, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 24)
  - Rochester, earl of., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 25)
    - Upon Nothing. "Nothing! thou elder brother ev'n to Shade" (Box 6, Item 25)
  - Rodger, Alexander., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 26)
    - Behave Yourself' Before Folk. "Behave yoursel' before folk" (Box 6, Item 26)
  - Rogers, Robert Cameron, 1862-., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 27)
    - The Rosary. "The hours I spent with thee, dear heart" (Box 6, Item 27)
  - Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 28)
    - A Tear. "O that the chemist's magic art" (Box 6, Item 28)
    - A Wish. "Mine be a cot beside the hill;" (Box 6, Item 28)
  - Root, George F., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 29)
    - Just Before the Battle, Mother. (Box 6, Item 29)
    - Tramp! Tramp! Tramp! The Boys are Marching. "In the prison cell I sit" (Box 6, Item 29)
  - Ross, Alexander, 1590-1654., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 30)
    - Wooed and Married and A'. "The bride cam' out o' the byre" (Box 6, Item 30)
  - Rossetti, Christina Georgina, 1830-1894., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 31)
    - A Birthday. "My heart is like a singing bird" (Box 6, Item 31)
    - Remember. "Remember me when I am gone away" (Box 6, Item 31)
    - Somewhere or Other. "Somewhere or other there must surely be" (Box 6, Item 31)
    - "When I am dead, my dearest" (Box 6, Item 31)
    - Parodies in the style of Rossetti, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 31)
  - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882., 2 envelopes (Box 6, Item 32)
    - The Ballad of the Dead Ladies. "Tell me now in what hidden way is" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - The Blessed Damozel. "The blessed damozel leaned out" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - Sister Helen. "Why did you melt your waxen man" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - Sibylla Palmifera. "Under the arch of Life, where love and death" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - Sonnet XCVII. "Look in my face; my name is Might-have-been;" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - Troy Town. "Heavenborn Helen, Sparta's queen,"Willowood. "I sat with Love upon a woodside well" (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 1)
    - Parodies in the style of Rossetti, source poems unknown. (some may be parodies of Oscar Wilde) (Box 6, Item 32, Envelope 2)
  - Row, Nicholas, 1674-1718., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 33)
    - Colin's Complaint. "Despairing beside a clear stream" (Box 6, Item 33)
  - Sackville, Charles, 1643-1706., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 33)
    - "To all you ladies now at land" (Box 6, Item 33)
    - Parodies in the style of Sackville, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 33)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 35)
    - Fog. "The fog comes" (Box 6, Item 35)
    - Parody in the style of Sandburg, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 35)
  - Sandford, Laura., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 36)
    - "Come to me, dearest, when I call;" (Box 6, Item 36)
  - Sargent, Epes, 1813-1880., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 37)
    - A Life on the Ocean Wave. "A life on the ocean wave" (Box 6, Item 37)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 38)
    - Everyone Sang. "Everyone suddenly burst out singing:" (Box 6, Item 38)
    - Parody in the style of Sasson, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 38)
  - Scott, Clement W., 1841-1904., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 39)
    - A Tale of the Tenth Hussars! "When the sand of the lonely desert has covered the plains of strife" (Box 6, Item 39)
    - Parody in the style of Scott, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 39)
  - Scott, Walter, 1771-1832., 5 envelopes (Box 6, Item 40)
    - Albert Graeme. "It was an English ladye bright" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - Allen-a-Dale. "Allen-a-Dale has no fagot for burning" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - "And said I that my limbs were old" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - "As the worn war-horse, at the trumpet's sound" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - Boat Song. "Hail to the Chief, who in triumph advances!" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - Bonny Dundee. "To the Lord of Convention 'twas Claver'se who spoke" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - Border Ballad. "March, march, Ettrick and Teviotdale" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 1)
    - Border Ballad. "March, march, Ettrick and Teviotdate," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - "Breathes there the map, with soul so dead" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - Coronach. "He is gone on the mountain" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - Farewell to MacKenzie, High Chief of Kintail. "Farewell to Mackenneth, great Earl of the North" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - "Harp of the North! that mouldering long hast hung" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - "The heath this night must be my bed" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - Helvellyn. "I climbed the dark brow of the mighty Helvellyn" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - Hunting song. "Waken, lords and ladies gay" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - "Huntsman, rest! thy chase is done" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 2)
    - "If thou wouldst view fair Melrose aright" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 3)
    - Lochinvar. "Oh young Lochnivar is come out of the West" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 3)
    - Lullaby of an Infant Chief. "Oh, hush thee, my babie, thy sire was a knight" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 3)
    - "O, Brignal banks are wild and fair" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 3)
    - "O, woman! in our hours of ease" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 3)
    - "O, woman! in our hours of ease," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 4)
    - "O, woman! in our hours of ease," (cont.) (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - "Of Brian's birth strange tales were told." (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Pibroch of Donald Dhu. "Pibroch of Donuil Dhu" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Rokeby. (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Romance of Dunois. "It was Dunois, the young and brave, was bound for Palestine" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - "The rose is fairest when 'tis budding new" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Soldier, Rest! Thy Warfare O'er. "Soldier, rest! thy warfare o'er" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Soldier's Song. "Our vicar still preaches that Peter and Poule" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - "The stag at eve had drunk his fill" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - "The way was long, the wind was cold" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - "With fruitless labour, Clara bound" (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
    - Parodies in the style of Scott, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 40, Envelope 5)
  - Seaman, Owen, 1861-1936., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 41)
    - "In Scotland, where the porridge grows" (Box 6, Item 41)
    - Parody in the style of Seaman, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 41)
  - Sedley, Charles, 1639-1701., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 42)
    - "Not, Celia, that I juster am" (Box 6, Item 42)
    - "Phillis in my only joy" (Box 6, Item 42)
    - To a Very Young Lady. "Ah Chloris! that I now could sit" (Box 6, Item 42)
  - See, the Conquering Hero Comes!, 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 43)
  - Seeger, Alan, 1888-1916., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 44)
    - I Have a Rendezvous with Death. "I have a rendezvous with Death" (Box 6, Item 44)
  - Service, Robert W., 1874-1958., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 45)
    - Parodies in the style of Service, source poems unidentified. (Box 6, Item 45)
  - Settle, Elkanah, 1648-1724., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 46)
    - "Great Sir, your royal father's general" (Box 6, Item 46)
  - Shairp, J.C., 1819-1885., 1 envelope (Box 6, Item 47)
    - Parody in the style of Shairp, source poem unidentified. (Box 6, Item 47)
  - Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616., 11 envelopes (Box 6, Item 48)
    - "All the world's a stage," from As You Like It. (Box 6, Item 48, Envelope 1)
    - "All the world's a stage," from As You Like It (cont.) (Box 6, Item 48, Envelope 2)
    - "Ay, but to die, and go we know not where;" from Measure for Measure (Box 6, Item 48, Envelope 2)
    - "Being your slave, what should I do but tend" from Sonnet 57 (Box 6, Item 48, Envelope 2)